welcome to this course on chat GPT prompt engineering
for developers
I'm thrilled to have with me either forfeit to teach this along with me
she is a member of the technical staff of Open AI
and had built the popular check GPT retrieval plug in
and a large part of work has been teaching people
how to use large language model of technology in products
she has also contributed to the Open AI Cookbook
that teaches people of prompting
so it's thrilled to have you with you
and I'm thrilled to be here
and share some prompting best practices with you all
so there's been
a lot of material on the internet for prompting
with articles like
30 prompts everyone has to know
a lot of that has been focused on the chat GPT
web user interface which many people are using
to do specific and often one off task
but I think the power of LLM large language models
as a developer to that is using API
calls to LLM to quickly build software applications
I think that is still very underappreciated
in fact my team at AI Fund
which is a system comfy to deep lonely AI
has been working with many startups on applying
technologies to many different applications
and it's been exciting to see
what LLM APIs can enable developers
to very quickly build
so in this course
we'll share with
you some of the possibilities for what
you can do as well
as best practices for how you can do them
there's a lot of material to cover
first you'll learn best
some prompting best practices for software development
then we'll cover some common use cases
summarizing inferring transforming expanding
and then you'll build a chatbot using an LLM
we hope that this will spark your imagination about
new applications that you can build
so in the development of
large language models or LLM that have been brought
the two types of LLM
which I'm going to refer to as base LLM
and instruction tuned LLM
so based LLM has been trained to predict the Nick's word
based on text training data
often trained on a large amount of data
from the internet and other sources
to figure out what the Nick's most likely were
to follow
so for example if you were to prompt this
once upon the time there was a unicorn
it may complete this
that as it may predict the next several
whereas are
that lived the magical forest with all unicorn friends
but if you were to prompt us with
what is the capital of France
then based on what
articles on the internet might have
is quite possible to the base LLM
will complete this with
what is France's largest city
what is France's population and so on
because articles on the internet
could quite plausively
be list of quest questions about
the country of france
in contrast an instruction-tunes LLM
which is where a lot of momentum of LLM research
and practice has been going
and instruction tune
LLM has been trained to follow instructions
so if you were to ask it what is the capital of France
is much more likely to output something like
the capital of Frances Paris
so the way that instruction tune LLM are typically
trained is
you start off with a base LLM
doesn't train on the huge amount of text data
and further train it further fine tune it
with inputs and outputs that are instructions
and good attempts to follow those instructions
and then often further refine
using a technique called RLHF
reinforcement learning
from human feedback
to make the system
better able to be helpful and follow instructions
because instruction tuned LLM have been trained
to be helpful honest and harmless
so for example
they're less likely to output problematic
tech such as toxic outputs
compared to base LLM
a lot of the practical usage
scenarios have been shifting towards instruction LL
some of the best practices you find on the internet
may be more suited for a base LLM
but for most practical applications today
we would recommend most people instead focus on
instruction tunes LLM
which are easier to use
and also
because of the work of open AI and other LLM companies
becoming safer and more aligned
so this course will focus on
best practices for instruction to UNOHAMS
which is what we recommend
you use for most of your applications
before moving on I just wanna acknowledge the
team from Open AI and deep Learned AI
that had contributed to the materials that easy
and I will be presenting
um very grateful to Andrew Maine Joe Palermo
Bars Power Ted Senders
and Lily 1 from Open AI
that were very involved with a spring stormy materials
letting the materials to put together
the correct learn for this short course
and I'm also grateful of on the deep learning side
for the work of Jeff Ladwick
Eddie Shu and Tommy Nelson
so when you use an instruction tuned LLM
think of giving instructions to another person
say someone that's smart
but doesn't know the specifics of your task
so when an LLM
doesn't work
sometimes it's because the instructions weren't clear
enough for example
if you were to say
please write me something about Alan touring
well in addition to that it can be helpful to be clear
about whether you want
the text to focus on his scientific work
or his personal life
or his role in history or something else
and if you specify
what you want the tone of the text to be
should it take on the tone like a
professional journalist
would write was it more of a casual note
that you dash off to a friend that holds the LLM
generate what you want
and of course
if you picture yourself asking
see a fresh college graduate
to carry out this task for you
if you can even specify
what snippers of text
they should read in advance to rate this text
about helentouring
then that even better
sets up that fresh college drag for success
to carry out this task
for you
so in the next video you see examples of how to be
clear and specific
which is an important principle of prompting LMS
and you also learn from either
a second principle of prompting
that is giving ltlm time to think
so that let's go on to the next video